<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: O'reilly | Guillem Fernandez]]></title>
  <link href="http://guillemf.github.io/blog/categories/oreilly/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://guillemf.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-16T18:46:25+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://guillemf.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Guillem Fernandez]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac OS X Productivity Tips for Developers: Display Control]]></title>
    <link href="http://guillemf.github.io/blog/2014/08/20/mac-os-x-productivity-tips-for-developers-display-control/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-20T16:53:14+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://guillemf.github.io/blog/2014/08/20/mac-os-x-productivity-tips-for-developers-display-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a small chapter about how to control the elements on the screen like windows organisation, windows switching and prevent from going to sleep. It&rsquo;s not the most interesting one but yet provides a bunch of tips that are good to know in the same line of the rest of the videos.</p>

<p>This post belongs to a series about <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/110000007.do">Mac OS X Productivity Tips for Developers</a>. Next post will be Applescript Automation &amp; Automator Apps.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac OS X Productivity Tips for Developers: Shell Tune-Ups]]></title>
    <link href="http://guillemf.github.io/blog/2014/08/19/mac-os-x-productivity-tips-for-developers-shell-tune-ups/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-19T17:11:59+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://guillemf.github.io/blog/2014/08/19/mac-os-x-productivity-tips-for-developers-shell-tune-ups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this chapter we are introduced to z-shell, an amazing and full of possibilities shell to work with. I have to say that I&rsquo;ve been told in the past about this shell, but never had the oportunity to dive into it. The main reason to not try it was the poor information I founded. Here Tim and Mathew introduces you to &ldquo;Oh My Zsh&rdquo; which is an awesome and easy way to install, maintain and customize zsh.</p>

<p>During the chapter you become less and less scared about moving to this other shell and see all the benefits, from moving from one folder to another, themimgs the shell or listing the options a subcommand has.</p>

<p>Again we are in front of a master lesson by Tim Berglund and Mathew McCullogh.</p>

<p>This post belongs to a series about <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/110000007.do">Mac OS X Productivity Tips for Developers</a>. Next post will be Display Control.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac OS X Productivity Tips for Developers: Web Service Helpers]]></title>
    <link href="http://guillemf.github.io/blog/2014/07/14/mac-os-x-productivity-tips-for-developers-web-service-helpers/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-14T07:38:38+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://guillemf.github.io/blog/2014/07/14/mac-os-x-productivity-tips-for-developers-web-service-helpers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this cruisade about keeping your hands far from the mouse and the trackpad, Matthew and Tim drives you into the world of the utilities to fetch and download information from the internet with commands. Here you can learn how to get information about the headers and bodys of the websites you need to work with from the terminal prompt. Also you can learn how to download and manipulate files or forward them and all at a few key presses from you, not the best one up to the moment but for sure one of the ones I&rsquo;m going to use more frequently.</p>

<h2>Pasteboard Command Line</h2>

<p>I decided to put this chapter together with the previous one because of its shortness. This is about how to use the clipboard from the command line as the title says. You never know how useful it can be until you realize the big amount of situations where it becomes a productivity improvement, not only to copy and paste data, but also to use commands and create gists with no mouse interaction.</p>

<p>This post belongs to a series about <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/110000007.do">Mac OS X Productivity Tips for Developers</a>. Next post will be Shell Tune-Ups .</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac OS X Productivity Tips for Developers: Saving to the Cloud]]></title>
    <link href="http://guillemf.github.io/blog/2014/07/14/mac-os-x-productivity-tips-for-developers-saving-to-the-cloud/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-14T07:03:54+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://guillemf.github.io/blog/2014/07/14/mac-os-x-productivity-tips-for-developers-saving-to-the-cloud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This time I was expecting to find something like &ldquo;how to use iCloud&rdquo; or a chapter based on how to use services like Dropbox or BOX, but instead of that, once again, surprise surprise, it&rsquo;s not about that. This is productivity tips for developers, so let&rsquo;s show you how to use the cloud in our benefit to store and share binaries, peaces of code or even social media content from the command line, all explained in a very nice way and providing all the information about where to find it, how to use it and where to get more info. I think I&rsquo;m going to start twitting in a very different way from now, without moving my hands out of the keyboard.</p>

<p>This post belongs to a series about <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/110000007.do">Mac OS X Productivity Tips for Developers</a>. Next post will be about Web Service Helpers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac OS X Productivity Tips for Developers: Viewing With Quicklook and Moving With Finder]]></title>
    <link href="http://guillemf.github.io/blog/2014/07/07/mac-os-x-productivity-tips-for-developers-viewing-with-quicklook-and-moving-with-finder/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-07T20:48:21+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://guillemf.github.io/blog/2014/07/07/mac-os-x-productivity-tips-for-developers-viewing-with-quicklook-and-moving-with-finder</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This review is about to short chapters. First one is about what to do with quicklook. As usual Mathew and Tim takes it one step beyond showing you which are the &lsquo;mush have&rsquo; quicklook plugins and how to use them even without removing your hands from the keyboard.</p>

<p>The second one is about the finder. I&rsquo;ve complained many times about finder and all the functions I miss in it, but there is certainly a few tips you can use to make the job faster, easier and more effective. As usual they drive you through this topic in an easy and very understandable way.</p>

<p>This post belongs to a series about <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/110000007.do">Mac OS X Productivity Tips for Developers</a>. Next post will be about Saving in the cloud.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
